

19-70 Seaview Drive, Port Moody, BC, V3H 0J9, Canada

□ (+1) 250-715-6128 | ■ mikeachester@gmail.com | ★ chester.io | • mchestr | • mchestr

Summary_

Senior full stack developer with 8+ years of complete product development lifecycle of successfully launched applications. My practical experience includes infrastructure automation, backend software development, application security, support, testing, and people management. I strive to keep up to date with the latest technologies and best practises and try to incorporate them wherever feasible.

Experience _____

Amazon Web Services

Vancouver BC, Canada

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

• Developer on AWS Cost Categories and AWS Cost Allocation Tags

Vancouver BC. Canada

April 2020 - Present

Feb 2018 - April 2020

Idemia

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- Project lead and backend Python developer working on core eSIM/SIM orchestration product
- Built highly available and distributed systems to asynchronously provision eSIM/SIM use cases from the ground up
- Responsible for communicating, designing, developing, and delivering multiple client projects from start to finish
- Built devops tooling to troubleshoot problems in eSIM/SIM provisioning
- Technologies: Python, Go, Clojure, PostgreSQL, RabbitMQ, Kafka, Salt Stack, AWS

Vancouver BC. Canada

Aug 2016 - Feb 2018

CA TechnologiesSoftware Engineer

- Full stack Java developer on the API Management Portal product
- · Responsible for designing, implementing, and testing real time API provisioning on remote API gateways
- Mentored employees on Python scripting and git best practices
- Built Python scripts to on-board new and existing customers
- Leader for an internal API first group, to help guide teams to develop APIs following best practises
- $\bullet \ \ \, \textbf{Technologies:} \ \, \textbf{Java, Python, Docker, Kubernetes, PostgreSQL, RabbitMQ, OpenShift, TeamCity} \\$

Siaras

Burnaby BC, Canada

May 2014 - Aug 2016

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Core Python developer working on the Siaras cloudScape/cloudBurst product
- Involved in designing, documenting, implementing, and testing custom plugins for OpenStack
- Developed solutions for abstracting different cloud technologies into a single common OpenStack API layer
- · Helped design and develop creative WAN solutions using a variety of technologies such as GRE, VPN, and L2 Gateway
- Implemented end-to-end tests which integrate into our CI/CD infrastructure
- Technologies: Python, MongoDB, OpenStack

Education_____

University of Victoria Victoria BC, Canada

BACHELORS OF ENGINEERING IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Sept. 2009 - May 2014

Publications and Awards _____

Dynamic web cache publishing for IaaS clouds using Shoal, Ian Gable, Michael Chester, Patrick

2013 Armstrong, Frank Berghaus, Andre Charbonneau, Colin Leavett-Brown, Michael Paterson, Robert Prior, Randall Sobie and Ryan Taylor

arXiv: 1311.0058

2013 Undergraduate Student Research Award, NSERC

References

Available Upon Request